adam.com.au 2012-12-15

# Legal | Adam Internet

## Copyright Infringement

Designated Copyright Infringement Representative

Adam Internet views the infringement of third party intellectual property rights (including copyright infringement) as a very serious matter. Adam Internet's Standard Form of Agreement and Acceptable Use Policy provides that account holders must not use Adam Internet's network or services for any unlawful purposes, including copyright infringement.

If an account holder uses Adam Internet's network or systems to infringe copyright, this may constitute a breach of Adam Internet's Standard Form of Agreement which may allow Adam Internet to suspend or terminate an account holder's service. Adam Internet has adopted a "repeat infringer policy" in accordance with section 116AH(1) of the Copyright Act 1968 and reserves the right to suspend or terminate its subscribers' accounts in accordance with such policy.

This page contains contact information for Adam Internet's designated copyright infringement representative under the Copyright Regulations 1968 (Cth).

All correspondence sent to Adam Internet in relation to the notification of alleged copyright infringement occurring on Adam Internet's network should be addressed to Adam Internet's Copyright Infringement Officer.

**Title:** Copyright Infringement Officer

**Address:** GPO Box 121, Adelaide, 5001

**Email Address:** [copyright.infringement@adam.com.au](mailto:copyright.infringement@adam.com.au)

**Facsimile:** (08) 8231 0223

## Privacy Statement

**Collection Statement**

Adam Internet is committed to providing you with the highest levels of customer service. This includes protecting your privacy. From 21 December 2001, we are bound by new sections of the Commonwealth Privacy Act 1988, which set out a number of principles concerning the protection of your personal information. 

This statement, called "Protecting Your Privacy Online", sets out important information about privacy protections which we extend to your personal information. It relates to personal information that you provide to us through our websites (eg when you subscribe to our services online).

**How we collect personal information**

Adam Internet collects personal information in a number of ways, including:

  * directly from you, such as when you enter your personal details on our websites (eg during registration or application for products and services);
  * when you provide information by phone or in documents such as an application form; 
  * from third parties such as our related companies, credit reporting agencies or your representatives; 
  * from publicly available sources of information; 
  * from the organisations identified below under "When we disclose your personal information";   

**How we use your personal information**

Your personal information may be used to:

  * identify you and to assist you to subscribe to our website services more easily; 
  * provide the services you require; 
  * administer and manage those services, including charging, billing and collecting debts; 
  * gain an understanding of your information and communication needs in order for us to provide you with better, more personalised services that are tailored to your needs; 
  * inform you of ways the services provided to you could be improved; 
  * conduct appropriate checks for credit-worthiness and for fraud; 
  * research and develop our services; 
  * maintain and develop our business systems and infrastructure, including testing and upgrading of these systems;   

**Personal information collected from our websites**

The types of personal information we collect from you will depend on how you use our web sites. Such information may include your name, date of birth, gender, current address, telephone/mobile phone number, email address, credit card details and your Adam Internet username or password. If you choose not to provide personal information, we may not be able to provide you with the services you require, or the level of service on which we pride ourselves.

**Other information**

Our websites record other information as well. This information is used to improve the structure and performance of those sites to provide users with an improved service. Whenever a page is requested from our web server, we record the time, date and URL of the request, along with information on the browser software that is being used. Adam Internet uses "cookies". Cookies are pieces of information that a web site can transfer to an individual's computer hard drive for record keeping. Cookies can make using our websites easier by storing information about your preferences on a particular website. This will enable you to take full advantage of the services we offer. The use of cookies is an industry standard and you'll find most major websites use them. Most Internet browsers are pre-set to accept cookies. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can adjust your Internet browser to disable cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used.

Adam Internet gathers usage information from our websites and other websites. This is aggregated for reporting purposes. Personally identifiable characteristics are removed and users remain anonymous, unless you have given prior express consent for Adam Internet to recognise your usage. This data is gathered by us to examine Internet trends and demographics and to assist in improving the structure and ease of use of our websites.

**When we disclose your personal information**

For the purposes set out above (under "How we use your personal information") we may disclose your personal information to organisations outside Adam Internet. Where appropriate, these disclosures are subject to privacy and confidentiality protections. The organisations to which we usually disclose information include:

  * outsourced service providers who manage the services we provide to you, including: 
    * customer enquiries; 
    * mailing systems; 
    * billing and debt-recovery functions; 
    * information technology services; 
    * installation, maintenance and repair services;

  * your representatives (eg your authorised representatives or legal advisers); 
  * credit-reporting and fraud-checking agencies; 
  * credit providers for credit related purposes such as creditworthiness, credit rating, credit provision and financing; 
  * our professional advisers, including our accountants, auditors and lawyers; 
  * government and regulatory authorities and other organisations, as required or authorised by law; 
  * other telecommunication and information service providers; and our related companies.

**  
Help us to ensure we hold accurate information**

Adam Internet takes all reasonable precautions to ensure that the personal information we collect, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, the accuracy of the information we hold depends to a large extent on the information you provide. That's why we recommend you:

  * let us know if there are any errors in your personal information; and 
  * keep us up to date with changes to your personal information such as your name or address. 

If you wish to access or modify personal information which you have provided, please send an email using the Contact Us page on the www.adam.com.au website.

You can access your personal information  
You have a right to access your personal information, subject to some exceptions allowed by law. If you would like to do so, please let us know by sending an email using the Contact Us page on the www.adam.com.au website. You may be required to put your request in writing for security reasons. Adam Internet reserves the right to charge a fee for searching for and providing access to your information.

**Security of your information**

We take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is stored securely. Transmissions sent to or from our websites are routinely monitored for quality control and systems administration. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to protect your personal information from misuse, loss and unauthorised access, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us or receive from our online products or services. These activities are conducted at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security. 

Credit card information is among the most important data we collect. Adam Internet operates secure servers to minimise the risk of unauthorised use of such information. Credit card information that is transmitted via our private network and is not open to transmission via the Internet. For obvious reasons, please do not send credit card information through unsecured email.

Our website may, from time to time, contain links to third party sites. To the extent permitted by law, we are not responsible or liable for, and give no warranty in respect of, any third party website or the goods and services offered on any third party website. We do, however, welcome your feedback or suggestions concerning them. Third party websites are not subject to our privacy standards so you should review the privacy policy and any other relevant notice that appears on a third party website.

**Childrens' privacy**

Childrens' privacy is very important to us. We ask that children under the age of 18 have a parent or guardian verify their membership application with Adam Internet. While Adam Internet will make every reasonable effort to ensure that children's privacy and other rights are not compromised, it is ultimately the responsibility of parents to monitor their children's Internet usage.

**What else you should know about privacy**

Remember to close your browser when you have finished your user session. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. You as an individual are responsible for the security of and access to your own computer.

Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information over the Internet (for example: in discussion forums, via email, or in chat sites) that this information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information in publicly accessible online forums, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your username and passwords and any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are using the Internet and our websites.

**How to contact us**

If you have any questions in relation to privacy, please contact us on 08 8423 4000 between 9.00 am and 5.30 pm, Monday to Friday. Alternatively, you can:

  * use the Contact Us page on the www.adam.com.au website to send your questions and comments via email; or 
  * write to our General Manager, at GPO Box 121, Adelaide, SA 5001.
